//javascript object notation

var questions = 
{
  easy: 
  [
  	{
		question: "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
		choices: ["DOS", "MAC", "C"],
		answer: "C"
	},
	{
		question: "Which of the following is not a database management software?",
		choices: ["MySQL", "COBOL", "Sybase"],
		answer: "COBOL"
	},
	{
		question: "Where is the HQ of Microsoft Office located?",
		choices: ["Silicon Valley", "Texas", "Washington"],
		answer: "Washington"
	},
	{
		question: "1 byte = ?",
		choices: ["4 bits", "8 bits", "16 bits"],
		answer: "8 bits"
	},
	{
		question: "An organized data is called?",
		choices: ["Process", "Storage", "Information"],
		answer: "Information"
	},
	{
		question: ".gif is an extension of?",
		choices: ["Image file", "Video file", "Image/Video"],
		answer: "Image file"
	},
	{
		question: "Which of the following is not a web browser?",
		choices: ["WWW", "Netscape", "Google"],
		answer: "Google"
	},
	{
		question: "In computer world, Trojan refer to?",
		choices: ["Virus", "Malware", "Spyware"],
		answer: "Malware"
	},
	{
		question: "A computer program that converts assembly to machine?",
		choices: ["Interpreter", "Compiler", "Assembler"],
		answer: "Assembler"
	},
	{
		question: "What is the maximum size of a word document created?",
		choices: ["32 MB", "124 MB", "999 KB"],
		answer: "32 MB"
	},
	{
		question: "Total number of function keys in a keyboard?",
		choices: ["11", "12", "13"],
		answer: "12"
	},
	{
		question: "The process of finding errors in software code?",
		choices: ["Compiling", "Debugging", "Testing"],
		answer: "Testing"
	},
	{
		question: "Which ports connect special types of music instruments to sound cards?",
		choices: ["USB", "MIDI", "HDMI"],
		answer: "USB"
	},
	{
		question: "What is the permanent memory build into your computer called?",
		choices: ["ROM", "RAM", "CPU"],
		answer: "ROM"
	},
	{
		question: "The smallest unit of information in any computer system?",
		choices: ["Byte", "Kb", "Bit"],
		answer: "Bit"
	},
	{
		question: "Maximum number of Primary Partitions that can be created on a Hard-disk?",
		choices: ["2", "3", "4"],
		answer: "4"
	},
	{
		question: "An error in a computer program?",
		choices: ["Bug", "Syntax", "Logical"],
		answer: "Bug"
	},
	{
		question: "BIOS stands for?",
		choices: ["Boot Initial Operating Startup", "Basic Input Output Startup", "Basic Input Output System"],
		answer: "Basic Input Output System"
	},
  	{
		question: "MVC framework stands for?",
		choices: ["Model-View-Controller", "Modern-View-Controller", "Mock-up-View-Controller"],
		answer: "Model-View-Controller"
	},
	{
		question: "Binary system uses the power of?",
		choices: ["2", "4", "8"],
		answer: "2"
	},
	{
		question: "GUI means?",
		choices: ["General User Interaction", "General User Interface", "Graphical User Interface"],
		answer: "Graphical User Interface"
	},
	{
		question: "Total number of pins in a serial port?",
		choices: ["10", "9", "8"],
		answer: "9"
	},
	{
		question: "Which one IP address cannot be assigned to a computer system in a network?",
		choices: ["192.168.1.1", "127.0.0.1", "192.1.1.27"],
		answer: "127.0.0.1"
	},
	{
		question: "The type of computers which can executes millions of instruction and billions of data per second?",
		choices: ["Mainframe", "Server", "Workstation"],
		answer: "Mainframe"
	},
	{
		question: "Repeaters function in what layer?",
		choices: ["Network", "Data Link", "Physical"],
		answer: "Physical"
	}
  ],

  hard: 
  [
  	{
		question: "Which is not a sorting algorithm",												 
		choices: ["Bubble", "Heap", "Sweep"],
		answer: "Sweep"
	},
  	{
		question: "Number of bit used by the IPv6 address?",
		choices: ["32 bit", "64 bit", "128 bit"],
		answer: "128 bit"
	},	
	{
		question: "Which one is the first web browser invented in 1990?",
		choices: ["Nexus", "Mosaic", "Internet Explorer"],
		answer: "Nexus"
	},
  	{
		question: "Which language is used for articial intelligence?",
		choices: ["Java", "C", "Prolog"],
		answer: "Prolog"
	},
  	{
		question: "Number of layers in the OSI model?",
		choices: ["7", "8", "9"],
		answer: "7"
	},
	{
		question: "First computer virus is known as?",
		choices: ["Creeper Virus", "Elk Cloner", "Rabbit"],
		answer: "Creeper Virus"
	},
	{
		question: "The altering of data so that it is not usable; for security purpose?",
		choices: ["Encryption", "Hashing", "Compression"],
		answer: "Encryption"
	},
	{
		question: "What part of a databse holds only one type of information?",
		choices: ["File", "Field", "Record"],
		answer: "Field"
	},
	{
		question: "Which one is the first fully supported 64-bit OS?",
		choices: ["Mac", "Windows", "Linux"],
		answer: "Linux"
	},
	{
		question: "The maximum number of rows supported by Excel 2007 spreadsheet?",
		choices: ["1,048,576", "1,342,554", "1,500,000"],
		answer: "1,048,576"
	},
	{
		question: "Which of the following is a programming language?",
		choices: ["HTTP", "HTML", "HPML"],
		answer: "HPML"
	},
	{
		question: "Protocol used to send email?",
		choices: ["HTTP", "SMTP", "POP3"],
		answer: "SMTP"
	},
	{
		question: "Protocol used to received email?",
		choices: ["HTTP", "POP3", "FTP"],
		answer: "POP3"
	},
	{
		question: "How many layers in the TCP/IP?",
		choices: ["6", "5", "4"],
		answer: "4"
	},
	{
		question: "How many users can access a shared forlder simultaneously from a Windows 7 machine?",
		choices: ["10", "15", "20"],
		answer: "10"
	},
	{
		question: "Contains specific rules and words that express the logical steps of algorithm?",
		choices: ["Syntax", "Structure", "Language"],
		answer: "Syntax"
	},
	{
		question: "A collection of related files is called?",
		choices: ["Record", "Database", "Field"],
		answer: "Database"
	},
	{
		question: "Storage that retains data after the power is turned off is refereed to as?",
		choices: ["Non-volatile", "Volatile", "Sequential"],
		answer: "Non-volatile"
	},
	{
		question: "Vanilla JS is a ?",
		choices: ["Framework", "Language", "Plugin"],
		answer: "Language"
	},
	{
		question: "rgb(0, 0, 0) = ?",
		choices: ["Black", "White", "Red"],
		answer: "Black"
	},
	{
		question: "Which below is not a design principle?",
		choices: ["Proportion", "Balance", "Scale"],
		answer: "Scale"
	},
	{
		question: "Which file format should be used for an image with transparent elements?",
		choices: ["JPG", "SVG", "PNG"],
		answer: "PNG"
	},
	{
		question: "Which is an example of a serif font?",
		choices: ["Helvetica", "Times New Roman", "Proxima Nova"],
		answer: "Times New Roman"
	},
	{
		question: "Iterative software development?",
		choices: ["Agile", "Waterfall", "Spiral"],
		answer: "Agile"
	},
	{
		question: "System for Data Analytics?",
		choices: ["TPS", "DSS", "MIS"],
		answer: "DSS"
	}

  ],

  harder: 
  [
  	{
		question: "What is the binary value of 'A'?",
		choices: ["01000001", "10001110", "11001100"],
		answer: "01000001"
	},
	{
		question: "Which is a pokemon?",
		choices: ["Umbreon", "Haskell", "Squeak"],
		answer: "Umbreon"
	},
	{
		question: "Which is a programming language?",
		choices: ["Parrot", "Boar", "Hawk"],
		answer: "Parrot"
	},
	{
		question: "Which is not a programming language?",
		choices: ["Monkey", "Cobra", "Eagle"],
		answer: "Eagle"
	},
	{
		question: "Which is not a framework?",
		choices: ["Dancer", "Seel", "Play"],
		answer: "Seel"
	},
	{
		question: "Which is a framework?",
		choices: ["Corsola", "Silex", "Zekrom"],
		answer: "Silex"
	},
	{
		question: "Choose a pokemon?",
		choices: ["Poco", "Grok", "Klang"],
		answer: "Klang"
	},
	{
		question: "Not a JS Framework?",
		choices: ["Ember js", "Knockout js", "Comet js"],
		answer: "Comet js"
	},
	{
		question: "A sequence search algorithm?",
		choices: ["Jump", "Radial", "Trigram"],
		answer: "Jump"
	},
	{
		question: "Differential equation algorithm?",
		choices: ["Borwein", "Euler", "Cipolla"],
		answer: "Euler"
	},
	{
		question: "6 foxes catch 6 hens in 6 minutes. How many foxes will be needed to catch 60 hens in 60 minutes?",
		choices: ["6", "10", "60"],
		answer: "6"
	},
	{
		question: "A bat and ball cost $1.10. The bat costs one dollar more than the ball. How much does the ball cost?",
		choices: ["5c", "10c", "$1"],
		answer: "5c"
	},
	{
		question: "3 birds sitting on a tree branch, a hunter shoots and miss, how many birds left on the tree branch?",
		choices: ["0", "2", "3"],
		answer: "0"
	},
	{
		question: "There are 23 football teams playing in a knockout competition. What is the least number of matches they need to play to decide the winner?",
		choices: ["20", "21", "22"],
		answer: "22"
	},
	{
		question: "A farmer has 17 sheep and all but 9 die. How many are left?",
		choices: ["7", "8", "9"],
		answer: "9"
	},
	{
		question: "In the final stretch of a marathon, you quickly ran by the person who is in the second place, what place are you in?",
		choices: ["1st", "2nd", "Champ"],
		answer: "2nd"
	},
	{
		question: "Which word is the odd one out: First - Second - Third - Forth - Fifth - Sixth - Seventh - Eighth?",
		choices: ["First", "Second", "Forth"],
		answer: "Forth"
	},
	{
		question: "In a darkroom and you have one match left, which do you light first, the newspaper, the candle or the lamp?",
		choices: ["Candle", "Lamp", "Match"],
		answer: "Match"
	},
	{
		question: "Which weighs more? A pound of iron or a pound of copper?",
		choices: ["iron", "copper", "none"],
		answer: "none"
	},
	{
		question: "var = false; if(!var != true){print true} else{false}; It prints ?",
		choices: ["error", "false", "true"],
		answer: "error"
	},
	{
		question: "ABC + 1 = ?",
		choices: ["2749", "274", "27489"],
		answer: "2749"
	},
	{
		question: "Decrypt the code: January: 71, Febuary: 82, March: 53, April: 54, May: ?",
		choices: ["35", "55", "65"],
		answer: "35"
	},
	{
		question: "'In two years I will be twice as old as I was five years ago'. How old is she?",
		choices: ["8", "10", "12"],
		answer: "12"
	},
	{
		question: "1/2 of 2/3 of 3/4 of 4/5 of 5/6 of 6/7 of 7/8 of 8/9 of 9/10 of 1000 = ?",
		choices: ["100", "1000", "10"],
		answer: "100"
	},
	{
		question: "How many times do the hands of a clock overlap in 24 hours?",
		choices: ["22", "23", "24"],
		answer: "22"
	}
  ]
}
